<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Fan</title>
    <link>https://davidfan.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidfan.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story of Princeton University Science Olympiad</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/posts/scioly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/posts/scioly/</guid>
      <description>Science Olympiad is a team-based STEM competition that approximately 8,000 middle school and high school teams compete in nationwide. Science Olympiad was a major part of my life from 7th to 12th grade, and an experience that I am very grateful to have had. In fall 2016 (my sophomore year), I cofounded the Princeton University Science Olympiad invitational tournament with Edison Lee. Co-founding this tournament and scaling it up to become one of Princeton’s largest student-run organizations, has been among the most difficult yet rewarding endeavors I have undertaken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes: Challenges of Organizing HackPrinceton</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/posts/hackprinceton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/posts/hackprinceton/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever attended a hackathon, you know how fun working on projects and learning in a fast-paced environment can be. There’s tons of technical workshops, speakers, mentors, great people, free food, energy drinks, hardware, and fun events. Maybe a bit of sleep too :)
A lot of work goes behind organizing a large hackathon like HackPrinceton, but not all of the work is “techy”. We grapple with many interesting logistical, communication, and management challenges, and I hope to give a glimpse of what some of those entail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>