<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on David Fan</title>
    <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on David Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidfan.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary for ShotCoL: Self-Supervised Video Representation Learning for Scene Boundary Detection in Movies and TV Episodes</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2021/06/paper-summary-for-shotcol-self-supervised-video-representation-learning-for-scene-boundary-detection-in-movies-and-tv-episodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2021/06/paper-summary-for-shotcol-self-supervised-video-representation-learning-for-scene-boundary-detection-in-movies-and-tv-episodes/</guid>
      <description>15 minute read.
Disclaimer: this paper summary exclusively represents my own views and DOES NOT represent the views of my employer nor my institution. This post should not in any way be treated as an official reference.
Roughly a year ago, I started doing research in self-supervised video representation learning with a focus on understanding long-form content. That work culminated in a second-author CVPR 2021 paper, which is the focus of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 2010–2019</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2020/03/reflections-on-20102019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2020/03/reflections-on-20102019/</guid>
      <description>Time flies! In 2010, I was in 7th grade and just beginning to mature. In 2015, I graduated from high school in NJ and entered college. In mid-2019, I graduated from college and moved from NJ to the West Coast for my first full-time job. To commemorate the ups-and-downs of the past decade, I decided to reflect on my experiences and what I learned from them. Those takeaways are condensed into four themes, in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story of Princeton University Science Olympiad</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/12/the-story-of-princeton-university-science-olympiad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/12/the-story-of-princeton-university-science-olympiad/</guid>
      <description>Science Olympiad is a team-based STEM competition that approximately 8,000 middle school and high school teams compete in nationwide. Science Olympiad was a major part of my life from 7th to 12th grade, and an experience that I am very grateful to have had. In fall 2016 (my sophomore year), I cofounded the Princeton University Science Olympiad invitational tournament with Edison Lee. Co-founding this tournament and scaling it up to become one of Princeton’s largest student-run organizations, has been among the most difficult yet rewarding endeavors I have undertaken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes: Challenges of Organizing HackPrinceton</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/11/behind-the-scenes-challenges-of-organizing-hackprinceton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/11/behind-the-scenes-challenges-of-organizing-hackprinceton/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever attended a hackathon, you know how fun working on projects and learning in a fast-paced environment can be. There’s tons of technical workshops, speakers, mentors, great people, free food, energy drinks, hardware, and fun events. Maybe a bit of sleep too :)
A lot of work goes behind organizing a large hackathon like HackPrinceton, but not all of the work is “techy”. We grapple with many interesting logistical, communication, and management challenges, and I hope to give a glimpse of what some of those entail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>