<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Fan</title>
    <link>https://davidfan.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidfan.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 2010–2019</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2020/03/reflections-on-20102019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2020/03/reflections-on-20102019/</guid>
      <description>Time flies! In 2010, I was in 7th grade and just beginning to mature. In 2015, I graduated from high school in NJ and entered college. In mid-2019, I graduated from college and moved from NJ to the West Coast for my first full-time job. To commemorate the ups-and-downs of the past decade, I decided to reflect on my experiences and what I learned from them. Those takeaways are condensed into four themes, in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story of Princeton University Science Olympiad</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/12/the-story-of-princeton-university-science-olympiad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/12/the-story-of-princeton-university-science-olympiad/</guid>
      <description>Science Olympiad is a team-based STEM competition that approximately 8,000 middle school and high school teams compete in nationwide. Science Olympiad was a major part of my life from 7th to 12th grade, and an experience that I am very grateful to have had. In fall 2016 (my sophomore year), I cofounded the Princeton University Science Olympiad invitational tournament with Edison Lee. Co-founding this tournament and scaling it up to become one of Princeton’s largest student-run organizations, has been among the most difficult yet rewarding endeavors I have undertaken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes: Challenges of Organizing HackPrinceton</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/11/behind-the-scenes-challenges-of-organizing-hackprinceton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/blog/2018/11/behind-the-scenes-challenges-of-organizing-hackprinceton/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever attended a hackathon, you know how fun working on projects and learning in a fast-paced environment can be. There’s tons of technical workshops, speakers, mentors, great people, free food, energy drinks, hardware, and fun events. Maybe a bit of sleep too :)
A lot of work goes behind organizing a large hackathon like HackPrinceton, but not all of the work is “techy”. We grapple with many interesting logistical, communication, and management challenges, and I hope to give a glimpse of what some of those entail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Short Bio I graduated Magna Cum Laude from Princeton University in 2019 with a B.S.E in computer science. I am passionate about advancing the state-of-art in computer vision and deep learning research, as well as reducing the computational and domain knowledge barriers that prevent large-scale production use of machine learning. I am currently an Applied Scientist at Amazon, and was formerly a software engineer in AWS AI.
My current research interests include: 3D vision, semantic scene understanding, multi-modal learning, and learning with limited or no supervision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to shoot me a message at anytime!
Email: dfan (at) davidfan.io
GitHub: github.com/dfan
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/davidfan97</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Industry Amazon | Research Engineer | Seattle, WA
July 2020 - present
 Doing computer vision research with a current focus on video understanding for Prime Video. Paper accepted to CVPR 2021 about a novel pretext task for self-supervised representation learning on long-form videos (i.e. movies).  Amazon Web Services (AI) | Software Engineer | Seattle, WA
August 2019 - July 2020
 Elastic Inference reduces inference costs by enabling users to flexibly provision GPU compute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Shot Contrastive Semi-Supervised Learning for Scene Boundary Detection Scenes are critical to long-form video understanding as they delineate semantic progression. Localization of scenes is an important problem that is foundational to higher-level tasks in video understanding. Movies are particularly interesting as they are longer, more semantically complicated, and more visually challenging compared to most video datasets which contain clean short videos.
We present a novel pretext task that exploits invariance in the shot-based scene structure of movies to learn a better representation via self-supervised contrastive learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://davidfan.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidfan.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-Reviewed  Shot Contrastive Semi-Supervised Learning for Scene Boundary Detection CVPR | 2021
[Paper], [Project page], [Code]
    OASIS: A Large-Scale Dataset for Single-Image 3D in the Wild CVPR | 2020
[Paper], [Supplementary Material], [Project page], [Code]
    Heart-specific Rpd3 downregulation enhances cardiac function and longevity Aging | 2015
[Paper]
    Topological defects as relics of emergent continuous symmetry and Higgs condensation of disorder in ferroelectrics Nature Physics | 2014</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>